How's Cassie?
卡西好吗？
She said in the last call we had
她在我们最后一次通话中说
that she was moving
in with Alex?
她在动
和亚历克斯在一起？
Yeah, seems to be going OK.
是的，似乎进展顺利。
Ah, good.
啊好。
He's a nice bloke, eh? Yeah.
他是个好人，嗯？是的。
I've been thinking,
when I get erm...
我一直在想，
当我得到呃...
..released, from here...
..释放，从这里...
..I'm not going to
come back to Shetland.
..我不打算
回到设得兰群岛。
Why's that?
为什么？
Oh, come on, Jimmy,
there's plenty
哦，来吧，吉米，
有很多
who think I let Donna
Killick off the hook.
谁认为我让唐娜
摆脱困境。
Are you going to eat
that Toffee Crisp?
你要吃饭吗
那个太妃糖脆？
Cos if you're not,
I'm going to have it.
因为如果你不是，
我要拥有它。
These are like gold
bullion in here.
这些就像黄金
金条在这里。
What time's the tribunal?
什么时候开庭？
Two.
二。
Don't feel bad about
the suspension,
不要觉得不好
暂停，
I've been fine.
我一直很好。
And if nothing else,
it gave me time
如果没有别的，
它给了我时间
to spend with my
dad, before he died.
和我一起度过
爸爸，在他死之前。
I wish I could've
made the funeral.
我希望我能
办了葬礼。
Couldn't be helped.
没办法。
What are you going to do,
if you cannae be a cop?
你会怎样做，
如果你能当警察？
I havenae really
thought about it.
我真的没有
想了想。
That's a big lie.
这是一个很大的谎言。
You've thought about
nothing but that.
你想过
仅此而已。
This committee has
been instructed
这个委员会有
被指示
to review the findings of
the police investigation
审查调查结果
警方调查
and Reviews Commissioner
和审查专员
into the death of Donna Killick.
唐娜·基利克的死。
We must decide whether a
charge of misconduct holds.
我们必须决定是否
不当行为的指控成立。
Is there anything you would like
你有什么想要的吗
to add in your defence
before we reach our decision?
增加你的防御
在我们做出决定之前？
I'm a police officer.
我是一名警察。
It's the only thing
I've ever done,
这是唯一的事情
我曾经做过，
it's the only thing
I've ever wanted to do.
这是唯一的事情
我一直想做。
And I really don't want
to jeopardise my chances
我真的不想
危及我的机会
of being cleared here today...
今天在这里被清除...
..but I have to say this.
..但我不得不说这个。
Donna killick was dying...
唐娜·基利克快死了……
..and she wanted
to punish people,
..她想要
惩罚人，
in particular,
Duncan Hunter and me.
尤其是，
邓肯亨特和我。
Now, she manipulated
Duncan Hunter
现在，她操纵
邓肯亨特
into committing a crime.
去犯罪。
And then she tried
to ruin my career
然后她尝试
毁了我的事业
through false accusations.
通过诬告。
And with all due respect,
恕我直言，
that was self-evident to anyone
这对任何人来说都是不言而喻的
who actually knew her.
谁真正认识她。
The fact I'm sitting
here today is a,
我坐着的事实
今天这里是一个，
is a victory for her...
是她的胜利……
..and no-one else.
..没有其他人。
We had no choice but to ask why
我们别无选择，只能问为什么
Donna Killick made
these accusations
唐娜·基利克
这些指控
and you know that very well.
你很清楚这一点。
We will now retire,
weigh up the evidence
我们现在要退休了，
权衡证据
and reach our findings.
并达到我们的发现。
We'll let you know
our decision, shortly.
我们会让你知道
我们的决定，很快。
Come on, Connor, hurry up,
we're going to miss the ferry.
来吧，康纳，快点，
我们会错过渡轮的。
All right, Sis. Get on, then.
好的，姐姐。那就上吧。
Oh, oh.
哦，哦。
Right, come on.
对了，来吧。
I'll see you later, at
your "book launch!".
待会见，在
你的“新书发布会！”。
Enjoy your swim.
享受你的游泳。
Connor not coming?
康纳不来？
He said he was.
他说他是。
Oh, I'll have to
start without him.
哦，我必须
没有他就开始。
OK, everyone, welcome
to the Kelpie Swim Club.
好的，大家欢迎
到凯尔派游泳俱乐部。
For those of you who haven't
been before, like Alison here,
对于那些没有
以前，就像这里的艾莉森，
the first rule of
wild swim club is...
第一条规则
野生游泳俱乐部是...
Never talk about wild swim club?
从不谈论野生游泳俱乐部？
Very funny, Ally.
非常有趣，艾莉。
But seriously,
nobody swims alone.
不过实话说，
没有人独自游泳。
So, grab yourselves a partner
if you haven't already, OK?
所以，给自己找个搭档
如果你还没有，好吗？
Leave a message and
I'll get back to you.
留言和
我会尽快给您回复。
Hi, Connor, it's me, I'm at
the swim. Are you coming?
嗨，康纳，是我，我在
游泳。你来吗？
OK. Bye.
好的。再见。
Hi. Hi.
你好。你好。
Will you partner with me?
你愿意和我合作吗？
Yeah.
是的。
I'm a bit nervous,
first time and all that.
我有点紧张，
第一次等等。
Of course, of
course, no worries.
当然，的
当然，不用担心。
OK.
好的。
Don't worry about keeping up
with them, they're hardcore.
不要担心跟不上
和他们在一起，他们是铁杆。
You doing all right?
你还好吗？
I'm good.
我很好。
Bloody cold, though, eh?
不过，该死的冷，是吗？
Shit.
拉屎。
Shit. Bryd, my leg. Alison?
拉屎。布赖德，我的腿。艾莉森？
I cannot feel my leg.
我感觉不到我的腿。
I can't... It's OK, it's OK.
我不能……没关系，没关系。
Just stop, just grab my arm.
停下来，抓住我的手臂。
I can't. Oh. Help. We
need help over here!
我不能。哦。帮助。我们
在这里需要帮助！
Alison!
艾莉森！
Are you OK?
你还好吗？
I've got you.
Alison, are you OK?
我有你。
艾莉森，你还好吗？
Thank God, Connor.
感谢上帝，康纳。
DI Perez,
通过佩雷斯，
we have reached the conclusion
that there is no evidence
我们已经得出结论
没有证据
of misconduct against you.
对你的不当行为。
You are free to return to
您可以自由返回
operational duties
with immediate effect.
业务职责
立即生效。
Congratulations, DI Perez.
恭喜，迪佩雷斯。
The right decision.
正确的决定。
I look forward to working with
you till the Fiscal returns.
我期待与
你直到财政回报。
God...
上帝...
..I feel like such a fool.
..我觉得自己像个傻瓜。
Don't be daft, Alison, it
could happen to any of us.
别傻了，艾莉森，它
可能发生在我们任何人身上。
Don't let it put you off.
不要让它让你失望。
Cold water exposure is
actually really good for you.
冷水暴露是
实际上对你真的很好。
It's made a big
difference to me.
做成了大
对我来说不同。
Certainly got the endorphins
going, that's for sure.
肯定有内啡肽
去，那是肯定的。
You'd better get ready for
your book launch, Connor.
你最好做好准备
你的新书发布会，康纳。
Aw, thanks, Connor,
it looks amazing.
哦，谢谢，康纳，
看起来很神奇。
Thank you.
谢谢你。
My pleasure, thanks.
我的荣幸，谢谢。
There you go, thanks.
给你，谢谢。
Folks!
伙计们！
Ladies and gentlemen, if I could
女士们先生们，如果可以的话
have your attention, please.
请注意。
Thank you all for
coming along to
谢谢大家
来
the launch of The Wulver,
The Wulver 的推出，
a new graphic novel
by Connor Cairns.
一本新的图画小说
通过康纳凯恩斯。
It's a story steeped in Shetland
这是一个沉浸在设得兰群岛的故事
myths and legends,
with a fair bit
神话和传说，
有一点点
of gore thrown in
for good measure.
血腥的
为了很好的衡量。
But erm, Connor is...
但是，嗯，康纳是……
..a great talent,
a boy from Glasgow
..一个伟大的人才，
一个来自格拉斯哥的男孩
whose love for
Shetland comes across
谁的爱
设得兰群岛遇到
in every page of this novel.
在这部小说的每一页。
I expect great
things from Connor.
我期待很棒
康纳的东西。
I know he won't let me down.
我知道他不会让我失望的。
Congratulations, Connor.
恭喜，康纳。
Aw, congratulations,
my wonderful boy.
哦，恭喜你，
我的好孩子。
Thank you, Jamie. Aye.
谢谢你，杰米。是的。
Well done, bro. Cheers.
干得好，兄弟。干杯。
Connor's dad not coming?
康纳的爸爸不来？
No, he's working. He
was desperate to come.
不，他在工作。他
迫不及待地想来。
Well, enjoy your drinks and
when you're drunk enough,
好吧，享受你的饮料和
当你喝够了，
come and buy a signed
copy of the book.
来买个签名的
书的副本。
Thanks, guys.
多谢你们。
I'm coming.
我来了。
Jimmy?
吉米？
Erm, I just thought I'd
drop round a wee gift.
呃，我只是以为我会
扔一个小礼物。
It's just to say
thanks for all the...
这只是说
感谢所有...
..all the help you gave
when my dad was ill.
..你给予的所有帮助
我爸爸生病的时候。
You didn't need to do
that, it was my job.
你不需要做
那是我的工作。
Yeah, I know that but you didn't
是的，我知道，但你不知道
need to spend as much
time with him as you did.
需要花尽可能多的钱
像你一样和他在一起。
And anyway, it's nothing,
反正也没什么
it's just a candle,
and a gift token.
它只是一根蜡烛，
和礼品券。
I love a candle.
我喜欢蜡烛。
So how did the tribunal go?
那么法庭是如何进行的呢？
It was today, yeah?
是今天，是吗？
Yeah, I'm, I'm back
to work tomorrow.
是的，我回来了
明天上班。
That's great news.
这真是个好消息。
You know, I know how
stressed you've been and...
你知道，我知道怎么做
强调你一直...
Listen, shall we
go for that drink?
听着，我们要不要
去喝那种酒？
Erm...
嗯...
..I mean, I've, I've been
meaning to ask you for ages.
..我的意思是，我曾经，我曾经
意思是问你很久。
It's, it's just that, you know,
with everything that was going on.
就是这样，你知道，
与正在发生的一切。
No, I know you've had
a lot on your plate.
不，我知道你已经
你的盘子里有很多。
We could give that
fancy wine bar a go.
我们可以给
花式酒吧一展身手。
OK.
好的。
I'm proud of you, you know that.
我为你感到骄傲，你知道的。
It's not going to top the New York
Times bestseller list, though, is it?
它不会超过纽约
然而，时代畅销书排行榜是吗？
That's not the point.
那不是重点。
You did this, it's good.
你这样做了，很好。
OK, it's really good.
好的，真的很好。
Will you sign my...? Oh.
你会签我的……吗？哦。
Er, no, er...
是，是，是……
..later, no problem.
..以后，没问题。
What's up with him?
他怎么了？
Has he never seen
anyone kissing before?
他从未见过
有人接吻过吗？
Look, I'm going to sneak out.
看，我要偷偷溜出去。
Cos I want to do a bit of drawing
before the sun goes down, so...
因为我想做一点画
在太阳下山之前，所以...
Well, I thought we could talk.
好吧，我以为我们可以谈谈。
We need to talk.
我们需要谈谈。
Right, later.
对了，以后。
At your place.
在你家。
OK.
好的。
The land is beginning to die,
土地开始死亡，
and the soil grows cold.
土壤变冷了。
So the Earth continues
its descent into night
所以地球继续
它下降到夜晚
and we mourn the
days drawing shorter.
我们哀悼
日子画得更短了。
Six months of light,
and six months of dark.
六个月的光，
和六个月的黑暗。
The Earth goes to sleep,
and later wakes again.
地球进入睡眠状态，
然后再次醒来。
Oh, dark mother...
哦，黑妈妈……
..we honour you this night...
..我们今晚向您致敬...
..and dance in your shadows.
..在你的影子中跳舞。
We embrace that which
is the darkness.
我们拥抱那些
是黑暗。
Without the night,
there is no day.
没有夜晚，
没有一天。
Without death, there is no life.
没有死亡，就没有生命。
Great goddesses of the night...
伟大的夜女神...
..I thank you.
..我谢谢你。
I am actually still
out of breath. Really?
我其实还在
上气不接下气。真的吗？
I am so glad it's
not uphill any more.
我很高兴
不再上坡。
Are you OK?
你还好吗？
It's fine, it's fine.
You are so slow.
没关系，没关系。
你太慢了。
Shut up. Ooh.
住口。哦。
Watch out, there's something
coming up behind us.
小心，有事
跟在我们后面。
Get off the road! What?
离开马路！什么？
Quick, Abbie!
快，艾比！
Ah!
啊!
Abbie!
艾比！
Ah!
啊!
So...
所以...
..what were you doing
on the hills so late?
..你在做什么
这么晚还上山？
A ritual.
一种仪式。
Lighting a candle,
that type of thing.
点燃一支蜡烛，
那种东西。
For the equinox.
为春分。
OK.
好的。
And on the way
back, this vehicle
而且在路上
回来，这辆车
forced you off the road?
强迫你离开马路？
Yeah, no doubt about it,
it drove right at us.
是的，毫无疑问，
它直接朝我们开来。
You think it was deliberate?
Is that what you're saying?
你以为是故意的？
这就是你说的吗？
Couldn't have been
anything else?
不可能
还要别的吗？
Come on, I'll take you home.
来吧，我带你回家。
It's fine.
没关系。
I'm good at the halls.
我擅长大厅。
Dad, what are you doing?
爸爸，你在做什么？
I should've stopped.
我应该停下来的。
I just hope those
girls are all right.
我只希望那些
女孩们没事。
We never touched them.
我们从来没有碰过它们。
I think we should go home.
我想我们应该回家了。
You go if you want.
你想走就走。
I'm staying.
我会留下来。
How do you manage to look
sexy frying sausages, eh?
你怎么看起来
性感的炸香肠，嗯？
Years of practice!
多年实践！
Now, leave me alone, will you?
现在，让我一个人呆着，好吗？
One of the guests might
think there's more on
其中一位客人可能
认为还有更多
the menu than just
black pudding.
菜单不仅仅是
黑色布丁。
Sorry I missed the book launch.
对不起，我错过了新书发布会。
Oh, can't be helped.
唉，没办法。
Go and see if the
genius is up, will you?
去看看有没有
天才来了，你会吗？
He's supposed to be giving
me a hand this morning. Aye.
他应该给
今天早上帮我一把。是的。
And you will give Abbie
a call, won't you?
你会给艾比
一个电话，不是吗？
She got a real fright
last night. Aye.
她吓坏了
昨夜。是的。
Two secs. Sorry, everyone.
两秒。对不起，大家。
Uh...
呃...
He's not there.
他不在那里。
He probably stayed with Bryd.
他可能和布莱德呆在一起。
Will you call her?
你会打电话给她吗？
Tell you what, I'll
change my shift,
告诉你，我会
改变我的轮班，
give you a hand,
instead. How's that, huh?
给你一只手，
反而。怎么样，嗯？
I'll do it, then.
那我来做
Here we go, folks,
sorry about the delay.
来吧，伙计们，
抱歉耽搁了。
Hello?
你好？
Hi, Bryd, it's Rachel.
嗨，布莱德，我是瑞秋。
Hi. Is Connor with you?
你好。康纳和你在一起吗？
No, no, he was
supposed to come over
不，不，他是
应该过来
to my place last night,
but he never showed.
昨晚到我家，
但他从来没有表现出来。
I tried calling him, but
he hasn't got back to...
我试着给他打电话，但是
他还没有回...
He's not with her.
他不在她身边。
He'll pitch up,
hungover, no doubt.
他会挺身而出，
宿醉，毫无疑问。
It was his book
launch, after all.
那是他的书
毕竟发射。
You want to take that
chance, after what happened?
你想拿那个
机会，之后发生了什么？
Rach, seriously,
just wait a wee bit.
瑞秋，说真的，
稍等一下。
Hey, Billy, what's up?
I'm just on my way in.
嘿，比利，怎么了？
我刚进去。
I've got a concern call
from a Rachel Cairns.
我有一个关注电话
来自雷切尔凯恩斯。
They're the folk that took over
the Noss View B&B on Bressay.
他们是接管的人
Bressay 的 Noss View B&B。
The son, Connor, he
hasn't returned home.
儿子康纳，他
还没有回家。
How old is he? He's 22.
他多大了？他22岁。
Two sugar.
两颗糖。
When was he last seen?
Yesterday evening.
他最后一次见到是什么时候？
昨天晚上。
A book launch at
the Harbour Bar.
新书发布会
海港酒吧。
Oh, there must be a
reason she's this worried?
哦，一定有
她为什么这么担心？
If there is, she didn't say.
如果有，她没有说。
Although, I did notice their
daughter was involved in
虽然，我确实注意到了他们的
女儿参与了
an accident last night.
But nothing serious.
昨晚发生意外。
但没什么严重的。
OK.
好的。
We need to swap.
It's OK. Don't worry.
我们需要交换。
没关系。不用担心。
All right, little girl, you
going to be good for Daddy?
好吧，小女孩，你
会对爸爸有好处吗？
Ohh. All right, there you are.
哦。好吧，你来了。
OK.
好的。
Hello. Good morning.
你好。早上好。
I thought you might need
this on your first day back.
我以为你可能需要
这是你回来的第一天。
Thank you very much.
非常感谢。
So, do you fancy a
wee trip to Bressay?
所以，你喜欢一个
下午去布雷赛？
I'll fill you in on the way.
我会在路上给你补充。
Sure.
当然。
So, how was the tribunal?
那么，法庭是怎样的呢？
Shite.
妈的。
Just glad it's over.
只是很高兴它结束了。
I was worried you
weren't coming back.
我很担心你
没有回来。
Yep. Me, too.
是的。我也是。
How about you? You getting
ANY sleep these days?
你呢？你得到
这几天睡不着？
Oh, couple of hours a night.
哦，每晚几个小时。
Why? Do I look knackered?
为什么？我看起来很憔悴吗？
Considering you've
being acting DI
考虑到你已经
扮演DI
and you've got a newborn baby at
home, you look as fresh as daisy.
你有一个刚出生的婴儿
回家，你看起来像雏菊一样清新。
Oh, thanks!
哦谢谢！
I can tell when you're
lying, by the way.
我可以告诉你什么时候
顺便说一句，撒谎。
I should probably work on that.
我可能应该为此努力。
Last year, Connor tried
to take his own life.
去年，康纳尝试
夺取自己的生命。
It was an overdose.
这是过量。
Some girl he was keen on at
uni was messing him about.
某个他喜欢的女孩
大学在惹他。
But he's a different person now.
但他现在变了一个人。
He's got a new girlfriend, Bryd.
She's been really good for him.
他有一个新的女朋友，布莱德。
她对他真的很好。
She's got him into
wild swimming.
她让他进入
野外游泳。
Personally, I think we're
panicking over nothing.
就个人而言，我认为我们是
惊慌失措。
So, where is he, Danny?
那么，他在哪里，丹尼？
Erm, Bryd...?
呃，什么时候……？
She's a house parent at
the Moray Bridge Halls.
她是一名家庭家长
海鳗桥大厅。
Your daughter was involved
in an accident last night,
你女儿参与了
昨晚发生意外，
is that right?
那正确吗？
It was nothing, just
a reckless driver.
没什么，只是
一个鲁莽的司机。
It wasn't nothing, Danny, she
could've been seriously hurt.
这不是什么，丹尼，她
可能受了重伤。
I meant it's nothing
to do with Connor.
我的意思是没什么
与康纳有关。
OK. So, when was the last time
you actually spoke to him?
好的。那么，最后一次是什么时候
你真的跟他说话了？
Last night. At the book
launch for his graphic novel.
昨夜。在书
推出他的图画小说。
Jamie is publishing it for him.
杰米正在为他出版。
Jamie Narey? Yeah.
杰米纳雷？是的。
Yeah. And before that,
what was he doing?
是的。而在那之前，
他在做什么？
In the morning, he
took his sister, Abbie,
早上，他
带着他的妹妹艾比，
to Lerwick on his scooter.
到他的踏板车上的勒威克。
She stays at the halls during
the week, when she's at school.
期间她呆在大厅里
一周，她在学校的时候。
And then, he went
to the wild swim,
然后，他去了
去野外游泳，
and then, to the book launch.
然后，到新书发布会。
So, he keeps busy, then. Yeah.
所以，他一直忙，然后。是的。
Is he on the Vulnerable
Persons Register?
他是弱势群体吗
人员登记？
No, we... we didn't do that
不，我们……我们没有那样做
because he wasn't keen
on people knowing.
因为他不热心
关于人们知道。
What about his is laptop?
Have you checked that?
他的笔记本电脑呢？
你检查过吗？
For what? If you're looking for a
suicide note, there won't be one.
为了什么？如果您正在寻找一个
遗书，不会有的。
Oh, my God!
我的天啊！
There might be an email explaining
where he's gone, that's all.
可能有一封电子邮件解释
他去了哪里，仅此而已。
I don't have his
password. Sorry.
我没有他的
密码。对不起。
Could we have a look
around his room?
我们可以看看
在他的房间周围？
Yeah... yeah, this way.
是的……是的，这边。
The drawings are for
his graphic novel.
图纸是为了
他的图画小说。
Is it a story about a
Wulver? Yeah, that's right.
这是一个关于一个
沃尔弗？是的，没错。
Half-man, half-wolf.
半人半狼。
You know the legends?
你知道传说吗？
Yeah, well, my dad used
to tell them to me.
是的，好吧，我爸爸用过
告诉他们给我。
Look, we know he's vulnerable,
看，我们知道他很脆弱，
so if you give us his
mobile phone number,
所以如果你给我们他的
手机号码，
and his social media accounts,
and a recent photograph,
以及他的社交媒体账户，
和一张最近的照片，
then we can try
and track him down.
那我们可以试试
并追踪他。
Thank you.
谢谢你。
Erm, sorry, but I have to ask,
嗯，对不起，但我不得不问，
if we have to identify him,
in case of an accident,
如果我们必须确定他的身份，
如果发生事故，
does he have any
piercings, tattoos?
他有没有
穿孔，纹身？
No, no.
书呆子。
But he does always
wear a gold signet ring
但他总是
戴上图章金戒指
with the letter "C" on it,
that we gave him for his 18th.
上面有字母“C”，
我们在他 18 岁时给了他。
OK.
好的。
What happened to your window?
你的窗户怎么了？
Er, not sure. The wind, maybe.
呃，不确定。风，也许。
It's brutal on this coast.
这条海岸很残酷。
If you were going somewhere,
如果你要去某个地方，
you'd take your laptop,
wouldn't you? You would.
你会带上你的笔记本电脑，
你不会吗？你会。
His sister being run off the road
is a bit of a weird coincidence.
他的妹妹被冲出马路
有点奇怪的巧合。
Did you notice the dad seems to
know a lot about police procedure?
你有没有注意到爸爸似乎
对警察程序了解很多吗？
I got the feeling that he
didn't want us involved.
我感觉他
不希望我们参与。
Yeah.
是的。
Let's run a background
check on him.
让我们运行一个背景
检查他。
Morning.
早晨。
Who's that? PC Lorna Burns.
那是谁？PC 洛娜伯恩斯。
She's been here a
couple of months.
她来过这里
几个月。
About bloody time.
Where've you been?
关于该死的时间。
你去哪儿了？
God, are you still here?
天啊，你还在吗？
Good to have you back,
sir. Thanks, Sandy.
很高兴你回来，
先生。谢谢，桑迪。
Passenger manifests.
乘客舱单。
No-one by the name of Connor
Cairns on any of them.
没有人叫康纳
凯恩斯在其中任何一个上。
Foot passenger? I'll check.
脚乘客？我会检查。
But there's no sign of the scooter
at either the port or the airport.
但是没有踏板车的迹象
在港口或机场。
Or of him from the CCTV in
the town centre last night.
还是中央电视台的他
昨晚的市中心。
Oh, Sandy, can I see the report
from the accident that the sister
哦，桑迪，我可以看看报告吗
从那个姐姐的意外中
was involved in last night?
昨晚被卷入了？
Yes, of course.
是的当然。
I was thinking, maybe I
should speak to Jamie Narey?
我在想，也许我
应该和杰米·纳雷谈谈吗？
He was supposed to meet
Connor this morning.
他本该见面的
康纳今天早上。
Yeah, that's a good idea.
是的，这是个好主意。
Look, let me sort this out and
I'll meet you at the Moray Halls,
看，让我解决这个问题
我会在海鳗大厅见到你，
and then we can talk
to the girlfriend.
然后我们可以谈谈
给女朋友。
Jamie? Hiya.
杰米？喂。
Can I have a quick word
about Connor Cairns?
我能说一句话吗
关于康纳凯恩斯？
Sure. I was just emailing him.
当然。我只是在给他发电子邮件。
Well, as you know, his
family are concerned.
嗯，如你所知，他的
家人很担心。
Erm, when was the last
time you heard from him?
呃，最后一次是什么时候
你什么时候收到他的消息？
I saw him at the
launch last night.
我看到他在
昨晚发射。
It's not great timing,
with his book coming out.
时机不是很好，
随着他的书出版。
Hmm. Did he mention any plans?
唔。他有没有提到任何计划？
No, but he mentioned an ex
on the mainland, recently.
不，但他提到了一个前任
最近在大陆。
Lynn, I think her name was.
林恩，我想她的名字是。
Do you think he could've
gone to see her?
你觉得他可以吗
去看她了吗？
Possibly.
可能。
I'm lucky to work with him.
我很幸运能和他一起工作。
He's such a talent.
他真是个天才。
So, were you surprised when
Connor didn't show up last night?
那么，当你感到惊讶时
康纳昨晚没出现？
Of course. It's not like him.
当然。这不像他。
Did anything happen last night
that might've made him disappear?
昨晚有没有发生什么事
那可能让他消失了？
Not really.
并不真地。
He said he wanted
to go and draw.
他说他想要
去画画。
Sometimes he likes to
sleep out under the stars,
有时他喜欢
睡在星空下，
if he's had a fight with his dad,
or he wants to commune with nature.
如果他和他爸爸吵架，
或者他想与大自然交流。
Does he not get on with his dad?
他不和他爸爸相处吗？
Well, they argue a
bit, but nothing major.
好吧，他们争论一个
有点，但没什么大不了的。
Although, there was one thing
that happened last night.
虽然，有一件事
那件事发生在昨晚。
Murry, from the library -
he was acting a little odd,
默里，来自图书馆——
他的行为有点古怪，
at the book launch.
在新书发布会上。
That's all I can think of.
这就是我能想到的。
Is that Connor's wee
sister over there?
那是康纳的孩子吗
姐姐在那边？
Yes. Do you mind if we
have a word with her?
是的。你介意我们
和她谈谈？
No, of course. Thanks.
不，当然。谢谢。
We just wanted to ask you a few
questions about your big brother.
我们只是想问你几个
关于你大哥的问题。
Is that OK? Sure.
那样行吗？当然。
So, how's he been lately? Is
there anything worrying him?
那么，他最近过得怎么样？是
有什么事让他担心吗？
No.
不。
Bryd was just saying that Connor
likes to sleep out sometimes.
布莱德只是说康纳
有时喜欢睡觉。
Do you know where that is?
你知道那是哪里吗？
No, I don't. Sorry.
不，我没有。对不起。
But he's got a
place that he likes.
但他有一个
他喜欢的地方。
His safe place, he calls it.
他称之为安全的地方。
I don't think he likes
being in the B&B much.
我觉得他不喜欢
在 B&B 很多。
Sometimes he says he'd rather
stay in the halls, with me.
有时他说他宁愿
留在大厅里，和我一起。
Is that because of
trouble at home?
是不是因为
家里有麻烦？
No. It's just a joke.
不，这只是个玩笑。
How's your wrist?
你的手腕怎么样？
Hear you were involved
in an accident?
听说你参与了
发生事故？
Yeah, I'm fine.
是的，我很好。
You know, if there was anything
that you wanted to tell us,
你知道，如果有什么
你想告诉我们的，
you can phone DS McIntosh
or me any time you like.
你可以打电话给 DS McIntosh
或者我任何时候你喜欢。
Nobody has to know.
没有人需要知道。
All right, then.
那好吧。
You know he's dead, don't you?
你知道他死了，不是吗？
Why would you say
a thing like that?
为什么会说
那样的事情？
I feel it.
我感觉到了。
I don't know why, but I just do.
我不知道为什么，但我就是这样做的。
Right, and who might you be?
对，你可能是谁？
Just a friend.
只是朋友。
Thanks for your help.
谢谢你的帮助。
There's definitely something
not right about this.
肯定有事
这一点不对。
You're not kidding. It's
like Salem in there.
你不是在开玩笑。它是
就像里面的塞勒姆一样。
We should head to the library.
我们应该去图书馆。
No, I... no.
不，我……不。
Er, I've got to go, I'll let
you know if I hear anything.
呃，我得走了，我让
你知道我是否听到了什么。
Sure. Absolutely.
当然。绝对地。
Hi, Murry. I'm DS
McIntosh, this is DI Perez.
嗨，穆里。我是DS
麦金托什，这是 DI 佩雷斯。
We're checking on the
whereabouts of Connor Cairns?
我们正在检查
康纳凯恩斯在哪里？
I've just heard. Has
nobody heard from him?
我刚听说。有
没有人收到他的消息？
Er, not yet, no.
呃，还没有，没有。
Are you OK?
你还好吗？
Yeah, I-I'm just really worried that
something awful's happened to him.
是的，我只是真的很担心
可怕的事情发生在他身上。
I catastrophise
about everything.
我灾难
关于一切。
How did the book launch
go, everything OK?
这本书是如何推出的
去吧，一切都好吗？
Oh, really well, I think.
哦，真的很好，我想。
Nothing odd happen?
没有什么奇怪的事情发生？
No tension between
you and Connor?
之间没有张力
你和康纳？
Er, no.
没有。
Oh, that's his book there.
哦，那是他的书。
Oh, have it, please.
哦，请拿下。
OK, well, thanks for your time.
好的，好的，谢谢你的时间。
If you do think of
anything, give us a call.
如果你真的想到
有什么事，给我们打电话。
All right, it is possible that
Connor Cairns has left Shetland
好吧，有可能
康纳凯恩斯离开设得兰群岛
of his own volition, but we
can't be sure of that yet.
出于他自己的意愿，但我们
还不能确定。
There could be more
at play here, so...
可能还有更多
在这里玩，所以...
This is a vulnerable young man.
这是一个脆弱的年轻人。
For the family's
sake, let's find him.
为了家人
看在眼里，让我们找到他。
Do we have any more
on the ex-girlfriend?
我们还有吗
对前女友？
Erm, Lynn Henderson.
呃，林恩·亨德森。
They were on the same course
at Glasgow University.
他们在同一门课程上
在格拉斯哥大学。
Chemical Engineering.
化学工程。
OK. Let's track her
down and talk to her.
好的。让我们追踪她
下来和她说话。
Find out if Connor's
been in contact.
找出康纳的
接触过。
Erm, Tosh, it would
be good to see
呃，托什，它会
很高兴看到
the background check
on Danny Cairns.
背景调查
在丹尼凯恩斯。
And locate the scooter, because
we can't rule out an accident yet.
并找到踏板车，因为
我们还不能排除意外。
And finally, erm...
最后，嗯...
..I don't want any of you to think
for a moment that I missed you,
..我不想让你们任何人认为
想念你的那一刻，
but... it is nice to be back.
但是……很高兴回来。
Oh - didn't take you
for a comics guy.
哦 - 没带你
对于一个漫画家。
Ah. It's just work.
啊。这只是工作。
Erm, hello. Hi.
嗯，你好。你好。
You look great. Thank you.
您看起来好棒。谢谢你。
Er, what can I get
you? Red wine, please.
呃，我能得到什么
你？请喝红酒。
Excuse me. Could I
have another glass?
打扰一下。我可否
再来一杯？
Here you go. Thanks very much.
干得好。非常感谢。
So, what's the comic
got to do with work?
那么漫画是什么
跟工作有关系吗？
Erm, we've got a missing person.
呃，我们有一个失踪的人。
And... he wrote it.
还有……他写的。
It's a story about a man
who conceals his identity,
这是一个关于男人的故事
隐瞒身份的人，
and it turns out
that he's a wulver,
事实证明
他是个狼人，
which is, he's
half-man, half-wolf.
也就是说，他是
半人半狼。
Yeah, I've met a few
of them in my time.
是的，我遇到过几个
在我的时代。
I'm sure. Me, too.
我确定。我也是。
Slainte. Here's to you. Cheers.
斯兰特。这是给你的。干杯。
Connor?
康纳？
THEY GIGGLE I can't
believe you just said that.
他们傻笑我不能
相信你刚才说的。
It was nice to finally
get that drink.
很高兴终于
得到那饮料。
Yeah. Yeah, it was.
是的。是的，是的。
Well, I'm this way.
嗯，我就是这样。
Yeah, I-I'm up there. OK.
是的，我在上面。好的。
See you around?
再见？
OK.
好的。
OK. Goodnight. Goodnight.
好的。晚安。晚安。
So fucking stupid.
太他妈傻了
Where have you been?
Just getting some air.
你去哪儿了？
只是来点空气。
Look, are you going to call
the police about last night?
看，你会打电话吗
昨天晚上的警察？
Listen we should talk
to the guests first.
听我们应该谈谈
先给客人。
Maybe it's some kind of joke.
也许这是某种玩笑。
Or maybe not, Danny.
或许不是，丹尼。
Morning.
早晨。
Oh, shit!
妈的！
You need to see this.
你需要看到这个。
Danny Cairns is an ex-cop.
丹尼凯恩斯是一名前警察。
Convicted on corruption charges.
因贪污罪名被定罪。
Served two years.
任职两年。
We need to know exactly
what you're involved in,
我们需要确切地知道
你所参与的，
and I need to know now.
我现在需要知道。
I was based in Ayr.
我在艾尔工作。
And I stole drugs from a young
drug dealer called Pepper Waldron.
我偷了小时候的毒品
毒贩叫 Pepper Waldron。
I was trying to put pressure
on him to become an informant.
我试图施加压力
让他成为线人。
It backfired.
结果适得其反。
He was killed.
他被杀死了。
Hit-and-run.
打了就跑。
A hit-and-run?
打了就跑？
That almost happened
to your daughter.
那几乎发生了
给你的女儿。
What's going on? Is it Connor?
这是怎么回事？是康纳吗？
They know. About me.
他们知道。关于我。
I'm sorry, we should've
said something. You think?
对不起，我们应该
说了些什么。您认为？
Do you realise how much
time you've wasted?
你知道有多少
你浪费了时间？
Is there anyone involved in
what you've told us that has
有没有人参与
你告诉我们的
a grudge against you?
对你怀恨在心？
Pepper's family blamed
me for his death.
Pepper的家人受到指责
我为他的死。
It was three years ago. They
don't even know where we live.
那是三年前的事了。他们
甚至不知道我们住在哪里。
They could have
found you, easily!
他们本可以
轻松找到你！
Is there anything else
that we need to know?
还有别的事吗
我们需要知道什么？
Last night, somebody broke in...
昨晚，有人闯入...
..and they stabbed all my
kitchen knives into the counter,
..他们刺伤了我所有的
菜刀进柜台，
and then, they left.
然后，他们离开了。
OK.
好的。
Let's have a look at the knives.
让我们来看看刀。
Sandy, can you get me any members
of Danny Cairns' old team in Ayr?
桑迪，你能给我一些会员吗
丹尼凯恩斯在艾尔的老球队？
And get me the details of the death
of a dealer called Pepper Waldron,
并告诉我死亡的细节
一位名叫 Pepper Waldron 的经销商，
and any family
members of interest.
和任何家庭
感兴趣的成员。
Yes, of course.
是的当然。
Look, I've just spoked to
Lynn Henderson, Connor's ex.
看，我刚刚谈过
林恩亨德森，康纳的前任。
But she says they only
dated a few times.
但她说他们只
约会了几次。
She says there was other
stuff going on with him,
她说还有其他
和他一起发生的事情，
and the family just
wanted someone to blame.
和家人只是
想要责怪某人。
OK, then.
那好吧。
I can't wait any longer!
我不能再等了！
Rachel, don't.
雷切尔，不要。
Leave the searching
to the police. Please!
离开搜索
给警察。请！
Oh, God.
天啊。
No...
不...
Lerwick Police.
勒威克警察局。
Rachel, what made you come
up here looking for him?
瑞秋，是什么让你来了
上来找他？
Well, I've been thinking
about his safe place.
嗯，我一直在想
关于他安全的地方。
So, I've been checking out parts of
the island which he loves the most.
所以，我一直在检查部分
他最爱的岛屿。
I have to ask you.
我得问你。
Why did he need somewhere
safe in the first place?
为什么他需要某个地方
首先安全吗？
For some peace and quiet.
为了一些和平和安静。
He's a sensitive soul.
他是一个敏感的灵魂。
And I would appreciate it if you
stopped the veiled accusations
如果您愿意，我将不胜感激
停止了隐晦的指控
against my family, and
you just find my son!
反对我的家人，以及
你只要找到我的儿子！
Tosh. Seal off the area and
get a forensics team up here.
胡说。封锁该区域并
在这里找一个法医小组。
Boss. Billy, this is
now a high-risk case.
老板。比利，这是
现在是高危病例。
Get Connor's photograph out on
the PNC with the usual notice,
把康纳的照片拿出来
PNC 通常会发出通知，
and get his information
out on social media.
并获取他的信息
在社交媒体上。
OK. And then, call the divers.
好的。然后，打电话给潜水员。
I'm going to need them to
take a look in the water
我需要他们
看看水
up at Stromness Voe.
在 Stromness Voe。
The Flett brothers'
boat's got a sounder.
弗莱特兄弟
船有一个发声器。
I'll ask Ally to
get over there now.
我会请Ally
马上过去。
And warn them that they
might... find a body.
并警告他们，他们
可能……找到一具尸体。
OK.
好的。
Sandy? So, I spoke to
a DS at Ayr Station.
沙？所以，我和
Ayr 站的 DS。
He says Danny's story about
the informant is a lie.
他说丹尼的故事
线人是骗人的。
He stole drugs to sell them on,
他偷了毒品卖掉，
and he didn't give
a damn who got hurt.
他没有给
一个该死的受伤的人。
Danny is bad news.
丹尼是个坏消息。
Sir. There's some locals
arriving to search for Connor.
先生。有一些当地人
到达寻找康纳。
I've tried to talk to them,
but they're determined.
我试着和他们谈谈，
但他们有决心。
So sorry to hear about your son.
很遗憾听到你儿子的事。
We're just visiting, but
we'd like to help if we can.
我们只是参观，但是
如果可以的话，我们愿意提供帮助。
That's good of you, but I wouldn't
want it to spoil your trip.
你这样很好，但我不会
希望它破坏你的旅行。
So, what do you think's
happened to him?
那么，你怎么看
发生在他身上？
We're not sure.
我们不确定。
Look, thanks for the
offer, but I've got to go.
看，谢谢
提议，但我得走了。
LOCKS VEHICLE Nicole,
what are you doing?
锁车妮可，
你在做什么？
Just being a concerned citizen.
只是作为一个关心的公民。
This isn't right.
这是不对的。
It's got to stop, now. No yet.
它必须停止，现在。还没。
Dad, come on.
爸爸，来吧。
OK, it's going to be light
for a few hours yet, so...
好的，会很轻
还有几个小时，所以...
I want you to go with them.
我要你和他们一起去。
I don't want to have to send a search
party out for the search party.
我不想发送搜索
参加搜索派对。
Does that sound OK?
这听起来好吗？
Who's that with Bryd Fleming?
I don't recognise him.
布莱德弗莱明是谁？
我不认识他。
I think he's staying at
the guest house on Bressay.
我想他会留在
布雷赛的宾馆。
Rachel.
雷切尔。
Look, there's a chance
that Connor might be hurt,
看，有机会
康纳可能会受伤，
so I think you should
leave this to the others.
所以我认为你应该
把这个留给其他人。
Look, if he is out there hurt,
看，如果他在外面受伤，
then I want to be the
one who finds him.
然后我想成为
找到他的人。
Yeah, I know how you feel but...
是的，我知道你的感受，但是...
No, you don't know how I feel.
不，你不知道我的感受。
Keep an eye on
her. Will do, sir.
密切关注
她。会的，先生。
Hey, there. We haven't
met before, I'm DI Perez.
嘿。我们没有
之前认识的，我是DI Perez。
Lloyd Anderson.
劳埃德·安德森。
Are those some of Connor's
drawings in there? That's right.
那些是康纳的
里面的图纸？这是正确的。
I was giving him
drawing lessons.
我给他
吸取教训。
Oh, how long did you work
with him? A few months.
哦，你工作了多久
和他一起？几个月。
He just needs some
pointers here and there.
他只是需要一些
这里和那里的指针。
So, you're an artist
yourself, then?
所以，你是艺术家
那你自己呢？
I am. I sort of make a living.
我是。我有点谋生。
So, you're not going
on the search, then?
所以，你不去
在搜索中，然后呢？
Don't misunderstand
me. I pray he's alive.
不要误解
我。我祈祷他还活着。
But that's not how it
usually plays out, is it?
但事实并非如此
通常会玩，是吗？
What, do you think
he took his own life?
你怎么看
他自杀了？
I can't say, but Connor was...
我不能说，但康纳...
He was too sensitive
for this world.
他太敏感了
为这个世界。
He took on board
all the bad stuff.
他上船
所有的坏东西。
Couldn't switch off from it.
无法关闭它。
It ate away at him.
它吞噬了他。
Hi, Ally, it's Sandy.
Have you found anything?
嗨，艾莉，我是桑迪。
你有什么发现吗？
Not so far.
不太远。
Don't worry how insignificant,
just let us know.
不要担心多么微不足道，
让我们知道。
We don't have time for this, Ally.
What are you expecting to find?
我们没有时间做这个，Ally。
你期待找到什么？
I just want to help if I can.
如果可以的话，我只想帮忙。
That baby is far too
beautiful to be yours.
那个宝贝太远了
美丽的属于你。
Carol Anne? Hi. Hello.
It's a long time, no see.
卡罗尔安妮？你好。你好。
好久不见了
Yeah, and I can see
you've been busy.
是的，我可以看到
你一直很忙。
Aye, yeah, she's, uh,
是的，是的，她是，呃，
keeping me on my toes.
Aren't you, Louise?
让我保持警觉。
你不是吗，露易丝？
Well, it is a tonic to see you.
嗯，见到你真是一剂良药。
You got time for another coffee?
你有时间再喝杯咖啡吗？
Yeah, got all the
time in the world.
是的，得到了​​所有
世界上的时间。
I'll give you that.
我会给你那个。
Oh, thank you.
哦谢谢。
That is mine.
那是我的。
Right.
正确的。
What good's this going to do?
这有什么好处？
Nobody should get
away with what he did.
没有人应该得到
远离他的所作所为。
Come on, move.
来吧，动起来。
Come on. Grab the bag.
来吧。抓住袋子。
That way.
那样。
Go.
去。
Connor. No.
康纳。不。
Connor.
康纳。
You bastards.
你这个混蛋。
You bastards!
你这个混蛋！
You bastards.
你这个混蛋。
You bastards!
你这个混蛋！
Did you see him, Dad?
你看见他了吗，爸爸？
I thought he was going to
have a fuckin' heart attack.
我以为他会
他妈的心脏病发作。
Oh, my God.
我的天啊。
The vehicle's registered
to Cameron Waldron.
车辆已登记
给卡梅伦沃尔德伦。
I could have told you
that. I recognised him.
我可以告诉你
那。我认出了他。
You're saying it's Pepper's family
who did this? Do they have Connor?
你是说这是Pepper的家人
这是谁做的？他们有康纳吗？
PHONE RINGS I don't know.
电话铃声我不知道。
Tosh?
结石？
We've found them.
我们找到了他们。
Arrest them.
逮捕他们。
Let's go.
我们走吧。
Where's Connor?
康纳在哪里？
We know about your brother.
我们知道你哥哥的事。
And we have the knives
from the Cairns' kitchen,
我们有刀
从凯恩斯的厨房，
which I'm pretty sure are going
to have your prints all over them.
我很确定会去的
让你的指纹遍布他们。
Pepper wasnae my brother.
胡椒是我的兄弟。
So, what was Pepper to you?
那么，Pepper 对你来说是什么？
My cousin.
我的表弟。
You blame Danny Cairns
for Pepper's death?
你责怪丹尼凯恩斯
佩珀的死？
But not the people who
actually killed him?
但不是那些
真的杀了他？
They wouldn't have touched
him, if it wasnae for Cairns.
他们不会碰
他，如果是凯恩斯的话。
So this is the only
justice I'm going to get.
所以这是唯一的
我要讨回公道。
Are you saying
you've harmed Connor?
你是说
你伤害了康纳？
That's your words, no mine.
那是你的话，不是我的。
Is that Pepper?
是胡椒吗？
I get the feeling you probably
told him a million times
我感觉你可能
告诉他一百万次
to try and sort himself
out, is that right?
尝试整理自己
出，是吗？
Nicole, I understand grief.
妮可，我理解悲伤。
You need a release.
你需要一个释放。
To lash out.
猛烈抨击。
Connor Cairns didn't
cause your grief.
康纳凯恩斯没有
引起你的悲伤。
So I'm going to ask you once
again. Do you know where he is?
所以我要问你一次
再次。你知道他在哪里吗？
Even if I did, I still
wouldnae tell you.
即使我这样做了，我仍然
想告诉你。
Your daughter's in
very deep water.
你女儿在
很深的水。
And if it turns out that
Connor Cairn's has been harmed,
如果事实证明
康纳凯恩的受伤了，
it's going to get
an awful lot worse.
它会得到
糟糕得多。
We didn't come here
to hurt anyone.
我们没有来这里
伤害任何人。
Why did you come here?
你为什么来这里？
What you've got to understand
is, Nicole loved Pepper
你必须明白什么
是，妮可喜欢胡椒
like a brother.
像兄弟一样。
More than a brother,
if I'm honest.
不止是兄弟，
如果我是诚实的。
They were so close
it wasn't healthy.
他们是如此接近
这不健康。
Then after Pepper died, she
became obsessed with Cairns.
Pepper死后，她
迷上了凯恩斯。
She did everything
to track him down.
她做了一切
追踪他。
But I swear she didn't
do anything to that boy.
但我发誓她没有
对那个男孩做任何事。
So his disappearance
was a happy accident,
所以他的失踪
是一个快乐的意外，
then you then used that
to taunt the family?
然后你用那个
嘲讽家人？
Aye.
机会。
She just wanted them
to suffer like she did.
她只是想要他们
像她一样受苦。
Abbie and her friend?
艾比和她的朋友？
That was you, wasn't it?
那是你，不是吗？
And the knives? Yeah.
还有刀？是的。
We just wanted to
give 'em a fright.
我们只是想
吓唬他们。
That was all.
就这些。
What's your instinct, DI
Perez? You believe him?
你的直觉是什么，DI
佩雷斯？你相信他吗？
I do.
我愿意。
So this was about rubbing
salt in the wounds of
所以这是关于摩擦
伤口撒盐
the Cairns family
and nothing more?
凯恩斯一家
仅此而已？
That's my call, yes.
这是我的电话，是的。
The preliminary forensic
report on the camper-van.
初步法医
关于露营车的报告。
No blood. No sign of a struggle.
没有血。没有挣扎的迹象。
What do you want me to
do with the pair of them?
你要我做什么
和他们一起做吗？
Release under investigative lib.
在调查库下发布。
Erm, are you sure
that's a good idea?
嗯，你确定
这是个好主意？
That's my call, yes.
这是我的电话，是的。
It seems a risk to
let them go now.
似乎有风险
现在让他们走吧。
What if they had accomplices?
如果他们有同伙怎么办？
Or they used a different
vehicle to abduct him?
或者他们使用了不同的
车辆绑架他？
I don't think they have him.
我不认为他们有他。
I think we should be
focusing on finding Connor.
我认为我们应该
专注于寻找康纳。
Get them off the isles and
get them out of my sight.
让他们离开岛屿
让他们离开我的视线。
Will do.
会做。
How's it going, anyway?
怎么样，怎么样？
Any sign of Connor?
有康纳的迹象吗？
Oh. Honestly,
哦。诚实地，
I'd rather not talk about
all that, if that's OK?
我宁愿不谈论
所有这些，如果没关系？
Actually I, uh, I bumped
into Carol Anne today.
其实我，呃，我撞到了
今天进入卡罗尔安妮。
And she was saying that
everyone at her work's got
而她是这么说的
她工作的每个人都有
a theory about what
happened to him.
关于什么的理论
发生在他身上。
Carol Anne Mane?
卡罗尔安妮马内？
Hmm.
唔。
Didn't you used to
go out with her?
你以前不是
和她出去？
Did I? Just-just
for a couple months.
我有吗？刚刚
几个月。
I thought it was longer.
我以为它更长。
What, are you jealous? Oh,
什么，你吃醋了吗？哦，
you think your man's
still got it then, do ya?
你认为你男人的
那时还是明白了，是吗？
I didn't say that.
Maybe she's desperate.
我没这么说。
也许她绝望了。
Oh.
哦。
What makes you so
keen to find him?
是什么让你如此
渴望找到他？
If your son was missing, you'd
want people to look for him.
如果你的儿子失踪了，你会
想让人们寻找他。
Ally, let's call it a night.
We've wasted enough time on this.
艾莉，让我们称之为一个夜晚。
我们已经在这上面浪费了足够多的时间。
Just a bit longer.
再长一点。
Y'know they found Pictish
treasure here in the '50s,
你知道他们找到了皮克特语
50年代这里的宝藏，
maybe we should go
for a treasure hunt.
也许我们应该去
寻宝。
It's taken millions of
years to make all this.
花了数百万
几年来完成这一切。
And now we're going
to destroy it.
现在我们要走了
摧毁它。
Are you listening?
你在听么？
I said there might
be treasure here.
我说有可能
成为这里的宝藏。
Really?
真的吗？
Yeah. Well, I could
do with some treasure.
是的。嗯，我可以
做一些宝藏。
Meg. Hi. Come in. Thanks.
Erm, I won't stay, though.
梅格。你好。进来。谢谢。
嗯，不过我不会留下来。
There's, there's a
party down at the beach
有，有一个
在海滩聚会
because it's the
equinox, apparently.
因为它是
春分，显然。
Erm, I just wondered if you
fancied coming for a bit?
呃，我只是想知道你是否
想来一下吗？
You know what, I'd love to,
but I've got work to do.
你知道吗，我很想，
但我有工作要做。
So, take a break.
所以，休息一下。
I don't think I can.
我不认为我可以。
OK. Sorry.
好的。对不起。
No, it's, it's fine.
不，是的，没关系。
Here, look, I'll get it.
来，你看，我会的。
Hi, Meg, you on your own?
You want to come and join us?
嗨，梅格，你一个人？
你想来加入我们吗？
Erm, thanks, I'm
meeting someone.
嗯，谢谢，我是
遇见某人。
Tea for two.
两人喝茶。
I'm sorry for being a dick.
我很抱歉我是个屌丝。
Well, it's fine.
You're here now.
好吧，没关系。
你现在在这里。
Cheers.
干杯。
Cheers to you.
祝贺你。
Listen, about earlier.
听着，差不多。
When you used your work as
当你把你的工作用作
an excuse not to come
out with me, you mean?
借口不来
跟我出去，你的意思是？
Is that what I did?
那是我做的吗？
It's OK. I get it. You're
protecting yourself.
没关系。我得到它。你是
保护自己。
You don't want to
get hurt again.
你不想
再次受伤。
But just so you to
know, neither do I.
但只是让你
知道，我也不知道。
Billy. Ally's sounder's
picking up something on
比利。Ally的发声器
拿起东西
the bottom of Stromness Voe.
They're bringing it up now.
Stromness Voe 的底部。
他们现在提出来了。
OK.
好的。
Sorry.
对不起。
Ally fishes here regularly,
it's been recently dumped.
盟友经常在这里钓鱼，
它最近被丢弃了。
It could be nothing, but
we thought you should know.
可能什么都不是，但是
我们认为你应该知道。
Oh, Jesus Christ.
哦，耶稣基督。
Connor?!
康纳？！
What the hell are
they doing here?
到底是什么
他们在这里做什么？
Sandy, keep them away
from here, Alex, help him.
桑迪，让他们远离
从这里，亚历克斯，帮助他。
Sorry. Stop right there. Is
it Connor? Please tell me.
对不起。停在那儿。是
它康纳？请告诉我。
Sorry, you are not
allowed any closer.
对不起，你不是
允许更近。
This is a crime scene. You
are not allowed any closer.
这是犯罪现场。你
不允许再靠近。
You have to stay
back. But it's my son.
你必须留下
背部。但这是我的儿子。
Sorry, but you
just have to wait.
对不起，但你
只需要等待。
Oh, God.
天啊。
It isn't Connor.
不是康纳。
Please go home.
请回家。
Well, if it's not Connor,
then who the hell is it?
好吧，如果不是康纳，
那么到底是谁呢？